No!
やめろぉーっ！
Dang...
こいつはぁ…
Dammit...
くそっ…
Dororo, your back.
どろろ。おめぇ背中が
Warm her back by the fire.
背中を火に当てろ！
Let go! Itachi...
やめろ！イタチ…
No, don't look!
見るな！見るな見るなぁー！
So that's how you hid it, Dororo.
こういう仕掛けだったのか…どろろ…
Let's go.
行くぞ！てめぇら！
Damn it...
くっそぉ…
Get back here, Itachi!
戻ってこいイタチー！
That's Papa's precious money...
それはお父ちゃんの大事なお金なんだ…
What's that?
なんだ？
Jiromaru...
二郎…丸
Jiro... maru...
Saburomaru...
三郎丸…
How it must've hurt.
痛かったろう…
How it must've pained you.
苦しかったろう…
Those bastards...
あいつら…
I'll kill them all.
皆殺しにしてやるぅっ…！
Jiromaru, eat them all up!
二郎丸ー！やつらを食い殺せーっ！
Betrayed this world
And it simmers within
Rupturing my innards
Swelling a reddish black
Until the sun burnt skin ruptures
There is a light
in the depths of the seething darkness
Confirming each other's voices
in the distance
As if to stroke with wet fingertips
I'd like to touch you one day
There is a light
in the depths of the darkness
Confirming each other's voices
in the distance
As if to stroke with wet fingertips
I'd like to touch you one day
#18 The story of the cape of no mercy
Are you sure we can trust that map, Boss?
おかしら…ホントにその地図合ってるんスかぁ？
There it is.
あれだ
I didn't need for anything
as long as I had you two.
お前たちさえいれば、他には何もいらない。
You feared nothing.
お前たちは何も恐れない
You were tied to nothing.
何にも縛られない。
Strong and beautiful.
。強くて美しい
Compared to you, how petty humans are.
それに比べて本当につまらない。人間なんて
Mama...
おっかちゃん…
Jiromaru!
二郎丸ーっ！
You two are flawless in every way.
やっぱり…完璧だぜ。お前たちはさぁ…
Humans are nothing but food
before your greatness!
お前たちの前じゃ、人間なんざただのエサだ！
Teach them a lesson!
思い知らせてやれ！
Bro...
あにき…
Dororo.
どろろ！
Jiromaru!
二郎丸！
Bro... How...?
あに…き、どうして
That shark...
あのサメ…
A demon.
鬼神…
That broken excuse for a human
is no match for you.
あんな壊れかけ、お前の敵じゃねぇや。
Rip those ugly humans apart!
醜い人間なんざ、ぶっ殺してやれぇ！
Bro!
あにき！
Jiromaru!
二郎丸ーっ！
Bro!
あにきー！
Bro...
あにき…
Hey, bro... Stop it, what the heck?
ちょ…あにきってば！なんだよいきなり
I came for you.
迎えに来た
Well, you took long enough.
ならもっと早く来てくれよ。
I had to go through
a ton of stuff by myself!
おいら1人で…すっごく大変なだったんだからな！
Bro...
あにき…？
He had your leg, huh.
あいつ…足を持ってたんだ
What a load of crap.
ハハッ…
You went through all this...
You killed Jiromaru...
そんなにしてまで…二郎丸まで殺して…
just to get a human body.
わざわざ人間の体なんか…
For what, huh?
何になるってんだよ…
Is it that important to you?
でも…取り戻したろう…！？
Bro, we can't just stand around.
Itachi is up there.
あにき…こうしちゃいられないんだ。イタチたちが！
This is the place. No doubt about that.
But this...?
場所はこの辺で違いなさそうだな。こいつは…
Boss, we can get in through here.
おかしら！こっから中に入れそうですぜぇ！
We're gonna be rich now.
これで俺らも長者だぜ！
Gonna have us the time of our lives.
へへっ！都で派手に遊ぶってのもいいよなぁ！
Hey, stop...
おい！ちょっと待て！
-What's that?
-There's something down there.
なんだこりゃ！
奥に何かあるぜ！
-Probably the treasure.
-Yeah.
お宝に違ぇねぇ！
よっしゃあ？
So that's the deal, huh.
そういうことかよ…
I knew you weren't
some good-for-nothing, Hibukuro.
やっぱただのズタ袋じゃなかったなぁアンタ…
B-Boss...
おかしら…
If you ain't got guts, go on home.
意気地のねぇ奴はとっとと帰れ！
Get the treasure or die trying.
It's one or the other, got it?
宝を手に入れるか、罠にかかっておっ死ぬか、2つに1つだ！
What's that?
ん？なんだぁありゃ
Bro, is that...?
あにき、あれって…
We found a boat,
probably the one Hyakkimaru used.
百鬼丸の乗ってきたと思しき船を見つけました。
There are signs of others
sneaking onto this cape too.
他にも多数、入り込んでいる者がいるようです。
I believe it's a band of brigands.
おそらく野党の類かと
No matter.
構わん。
Kill every human being who is a threat
to the peace of our people.
民の安寧を脅かす者ども、1人たりとも生きて帰すな！
March!
全軍進め！
They're Daigo's samurai.
ありゃ醍醐の侍か…
Why the heck are they here?
なんだってこんなとこまで…
They're not here
to take my treasure, are they?
まさかあいつら、俺のお宝を横取りする気じゃねぇよな
Hey, the treasure isn't just yours.
おい、いつからテメェ1人のモンになったんだ
Arrows!
矢が！
Orders are to not leave
a single rat alive. Release!
1匹たりとも逃がすなとのご命令だ！撃てぇー！
What the heck is going on?
どうなってんスかおかしらぁ！
The loot was almost in my grasp...
チッ…お宝は目の前だってのに！
They're all over the beach.
We need to find a place to hide.
浜辺は侍でいっぱいだ。いっぺんどっかに隠れてやり過ごそう！
There they are!
いたぞ！
Jiromaru...
二郎丸…
Saburomaru...
三郎丸…
We'll be together, forever.
俺たちはどこまでだって一緒だ…
Just give me a few minutes.
もうちっとだけ待っててくれ…
And I'll head over
with a load of gifts for you.
たんまり土産、持ってくからよ…
-Not over there.
-Must be this way.
こっちはいない！
じゃあこっちだ！
-Itachi.
-Hey, Dororo.
あっ…イタチ！
どろろか…
You've got a lot of luck
in that tiny frame.
おめぇもしぶとさだけは一丁前だなぁ
Don't worry. Your papa's treasure
is still up in that mountain.
安心しな。お父ちゃんのお宝はまだあの山ん中だぜ。
There were traps everywhere.
One wrong step, and boom, you're done.
あっちこっち罠が仕掛けてあってなぁ。
ヘタにいじるとたちまちドカンだ。
I could've disarmed them
if I had the time.
時がありゃ取り除いてやれるんだが
This isn't the time for that!
Forget the loot, we have to run.
言ってる場合かよ！宝なんてどうでもいいから逃げねぇと！
What if the samurai find it first?
侍どもに見つけられたら終わりだ！
I can't have them using my money
for some stupid wars.
俺のカネを、くだらねぇ戦なんざに使われてたまるか！
Boom.
ドカン。
Us, too. Boom.
こっちも、ドカン
What are you talking about?
あにき…何言ってんの？
Actually Dororo, it might just work.
いや…上手くいくかもしれねぇぜ、どろろ
They must be hidden around here.
Scour the area.
この辺りに隠れているはずだ。徹底的に探せ！
H-Help me...
助け…て…
They have explosives...
奴…火薬を…持って…いて…
Call the other troop back, now!
チッ…別働隊の連中も呼び戻せ！急ぐぞ！
We gotta get to the beach
before they realize it's a decoy.
囮とバレたら、すぐに戻ってくる。今のうちに浜へ出るぞ
The demon harming our land of Daigo.
Hyakkimaru!
我が醍醐の国に仇なす鬼神
百鬼丸！
Bro...
あにき…
Tahomaru...!
多…宝…丸！
All that side with the demon
will die here!
鬼神に与する者ともども、ここで成敗する！
Why?
なぜ！
Bro!
あにきー！
Now's our chance, let's run!
今のうちだ！ずらかるぞ！
But bro...
けど、あにきが！
We'll all die if we stay, we gotta run!
このままじゃどのみち全滅だ！一旦退け！
Bro!
あにきぃっ！
Hyogo!
兵庫！
He's not like before. Why?
違う…この前とは…なぜ…
Young Master is heir to the land of Daigo.
若は醍醐の国の後継。
Its people, its prosperity.
民の命と、国の行く末。
He bears it all on his shoulders.
そのすべてを背負っておられる。
His resolve far exceeds yours.
覚悟が違うのだ
Why kill me?
なぜ俺を…殺す？
Your existence alone
貴様が生きているだけで、
causes calamities to befall our land.
醍醐の国は厄災に見舞われ続ける。
You are the enemy of the people of Daigo!
貴様は、我ら醍醐の敵だ！
Release!
撃てぇーっ！
Dammit, we gotta hide somewhere.
ちくしょう…どっか隠れられる場所！
Hey, this place was on your map.
ここは…おめぇの地図にあった
This might be another trap, but...
こいつも…罠かもしれねぇが…
the fifth stone from the left is a clue.
弓手から5番目に、何か手がかりが…
Itachi, give it up already.
イタチ！もう諦めなよ！
We could go and live in a better place.
All we need is this treasure.
これがあれは…俺たちはもっとましなところに行けるんだ…
Itachi!
イタチ！
This is the end!
ここで終わらせる！
I will shoot you down.
You and all that side with you!
討ち果たす！貴様も、貴様に与する者もすべて！
What am I supposed to do now, bro?
どうすりゃいいんだよあにきー！
Young Master, finish him!
若！とどめを！
Enemies...
敵…！
You are my enemies.
敵…お前たちは…俺の…！
I won't let you.
やらせない…！
I will break that left arm of yours, too,
Hyakkimaru.
その左腕の刀も、へし折ってやる。百鬼丸！
Itachi, hang in there.
イタチ、しっかり！
Dororo, one last favor.
ど…どろろ…頼む…
Let me see the treasure,
just one glimpse...
俺に一度だけ…カネを拝ませて…
I beg you...
くれ…
You're all going to where
Jiromaru and Saburomaru went.
お前たち…みんな…二郎丸と三郎丸のところへ行け…
No, Dororo!
はっ！どろろ！
-Young Master!
-Mutsu, Hyogo, retreat!
若！
陸奥、兵庫！退け！
Dororo.
どろろ…！
Hyogo...
兵庫！
Hyogo... Hyogo!
兵庫…兵庫！
Itachi, Itachi!
イタチ、イタチ！
Money...
カネ…
There it is... It's really there...
あった…あったぜ…
My money...
俺の…カ…ネ…
When you meet Papa up there,
don't quarrel with him this time.
あっちでお父ちゃんと会っても、今度はケンカしないでおくれよ？
What you have on your back
can move people and change the world.
お前さんの背中のそれは、人を動かし世を変える、
It's a source of great power.
でかい力の源になる
I don't know how I should use this stuff,
so I don't want it yet.
おいらには、こいつの使い方がわかんないからさ…今はまだ
Papa, Mama.
Wait a bit more 'till I figure it out.
お父ちゃん…おっかちゃん。もうちょっとだけ待ってておくんな
Hold on a sec.
ちょ…ちょっと待って。
This is different, okay?
これはその…別勘定だから。
Just a little something to keep us going.
当然の軍資金ってやつだから。な？
Hey, hold up!
あ…待ってよあにき！
Born into this world
There is no salvation
The distorted shape of the heart
Yet it beats courageously
There is no turning back
Even from the path of evil
Witnessing the withering seasons
We search for the truth
In our ugliness
We don't even recognize the pain
As we peel back the skin
We are forever tormented by our stupidity
But if the dawn never comes
Through the painful night
You who distrusts nothing
You will be able to love
this accursed world
Now that we carry the world
on our shoulders
It's time to take it back
"Jiromaru"